<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SWEBOK on Ebeid ElSayed</title>
    <link>https://ebeid.github.io/tags/swebok/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SWEBOK on Ebeid ElSayed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 18:54:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ebeid.github.io/tags/swebok/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I prepared for CSDP ?</title>
      <link>https://ebeid.github.io/blog/2010-12-27-how-i-prepared-for-csdp.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 18:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebeid.github.io/blog/2010-12-27-how-i-prepared-for-csdp.html/</guid>
      <description>After I became an IEEE Certified Software Development Professional, many of my friends asked me about it and how to prepare for it. As a CSDP holder, let me introduce CSDP for you and how I prepared for it.
The CSDP credential is intended for mid-career software development professionals that want to confirm their proficiency of standard software development practices and advance in their careers.
Who is eligible to take the CSDP?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to educate the next generation of software engineers ?</title>
      <link>https://ebeid.github.io/blog/2010-09-01-how-to-educate-next-generation-of.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 05:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebeid.github.io/blog/2010-09-01-how-to-educate-next-generation-of.html/</guid>
      <description>After my completion of my master in software engineering at Nile University which we faced many problems at it (I hope it be better in the future), I tried to search for what globally constitutes a master of software engineering and I found the following:
 The last effort to create a reference curriculum for graduate software engineering education was by the SEI in the early 1990s. There were, in effect, no current community-endorsed recommendations on what to teach software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the SWEBOK Guide?</title>
      <link>https://ebeid.github.io/blog/2010-04-10-what-is-swebok-guide.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 20:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebeid.github.io/blog/2010-04-10-what-is-swebok-guide.html/</guid>
      <description># SWEBOK or Software Engineering Body Of Knowledge is an all-inclusive term that describes the sum of knowledge within the profession of software engineering. Since it is usually not possible to put the full body of knowledge of even an emerging discipline, such as software engineering, into a single document, there is a need for a Guide to the Software Engineering Body of Knowledge. This Guide will seek to identify and describe that subset of the body of knowledge that is generally accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>